>> Jem Young: 我现在想做的下一步是我们成功登录
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Next thing I wanna do
now that we're successfully logged in
我们的服务器，我们知道我们的服务器有或者我们的新用户具有路由访问权。
our server, we know our server has or
our new user has route access.
我们要禁用路线卡兹还记得那些试图进入的人
We're gonna disable route, cuz remember
all those people trying to get in,
这对他们是没有好处的
it's never beneficial for
them to get in as route.
而路由是更常见的用户名之一，因此
And route is one of the more
common username, so
他们也会把它弄坏的
they're gonna try to break it as well.
>> Jem Young: 我们首先要做的是
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: First
thing we need to do is,
实际上不需要此更改许可权。
actually don't need this
change the permissions.
但现在我们要换权限了
But for
now we're gonna change permissions, so
它是我们的用户阅读和阅读的
that it's read and readable by our users.
所以你可能要 sudo chmod 644 和那个授权的密钥文件。
So you're gonna probably sudo chmod
644 and that authorized key file.
所以我要在这里做这个，在我的服务器上。 所以我们会知道我是否需要起诉
So I'm gonna do that here, in my server.
So, we'll see if I need sudo.
chmod 644 -/ .ssh/authorized_keys。
chmod 644 -/ .ssh/authorized_keys.
太酷了这只需要苏多
Cool, didn't need sudo for that one.
我们确实需要做这一步
And we actually did need to do this step,
但根据您的服务器设置，您可能需要执行该操作。
but depending on what your server is
set up as, you may need to do it.
所以我把它加到了未来
So I just added it in there for
the future,
就能为自己打发子弹
just kinda bullet proofing ourselves.
我们现在所做的就是改变这个文件的权限
And all we're doing is changing
that the permissions that file so
都不是人人都能读读的
they're not reading readable by everybody.
他们只会让我自己去读读
They're only readable and
rattled by sudo, myself, and
某些文件系统守护程序，如 SSH 守护程序。
certain file system daemons,
like SSH daemon.
>> Jem Young: 下一步，我们将禁用 root 用户登录。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Next thing we're gonna do,
now we're gonna disable root login.
所以我们要修改我们的 SSH 配置
So we're gonna modify our SSH config, or
服务器本身的 SSH 守护程序配置。
the SSH daemon config
on our server itself.
苏多维
So sudo vi
/etc/ssh/sshd_config 。
/etc/ssh/sshd_config.
记住，你总是可以选择完成的，大部分都是这样。
And remember, you can always
tab complete and most of this.
让我们说
Let'say sudo
vi /etc/ssh/sshd_config，
vi /etc/ssh/sshd_config,
我的密码
my password.
现在我们在 SSH 守护程序配置中。 守护程序是一个程序
And now we're in the SSH daemon config.
The daemon is a program that's always
在后台运行。
running in the background.
这就是我们的 SSH ，我们不需要做任何事情来启动它。
And that's what allows us the SSH and
we don't need to do anything to start it.
我们不需要做任何事情来阻止它。 它一直在不停地运转
We don't need to do anything to stop it.
It's just constantly running and
听我说 我们会禁用 RootLogin
listening.
And we're gonna disable RootLogin.
> > Jem Young: 所以我要编辑，把它转换成一个不。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So I'm just gonna edit and
switch that to a no.
这里还有什么我想改变的吗
Is there anything else
I wanna change in here?
PubkeyAuthentication ，这就行了。
PubkeyAuthentication, that's fine.
StrictMode，我现在就离开它。
StrictMode, I'll leave it as is for now.
我不想搞得太乱了
I don't wanna mess too much with it.
但是通过 SSH 守护程序，您可以执行大量的操作，例如启用密码登录，
But with SSH daemon, you can do lots
of things like enable password login,
禁用密码登录。
disable password login.
具有最大重试次数，因此用户只能重试特定时间
Have max retry, so someone can only
retry a certain amount of time for
把它们完全地带在一段时间里
just bands them completely for
a certain amount of time.
您可以作为一个用户登录的最大次数，例如。
Maximum number of times you can be
logged in as one user, things like that.
我们现在就走吧
We're gonna leave that alone for now.
要谨慎，任何时候使用 sudo 意味着你能做点什么
A word of caution, anytime you're using
sudo means you can do something really
危险用于修改 SSH 守护程序配置。
dangerous for
modifying SSH daemon configuration.
您可以通过将自己锁定在自己的服务器之外的方式对其进行修改，
You can modify it in such a way that you
can lock yourself out of your own server,
那就太尴尬了
which would be pretty embarrassing.
但如果再次发生这种情况，你很快就会赶上。
But if that happens to start over again,
you'll catch up pretty quickly.
这不是世界末日。
It's not the end of the world.
如果您有生产服务器，那么这些都成为真正的大交易
These all become a real big deal if
you have a production server and
你把自己关在生产服务里
you lock yourself out of production
serve,r known to get in and
好的好的
yeah [LAUGH]
Yes.
>> 扬声器 2: 您已更改端口。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: You've changed the port.
>> Jem Young: 我不，这类的情况，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: I don't, for
the case of this class,
但他们发现改变港口的很多人都是很有帮助的
but a lot of people they find
changing the port is helpful support.
缺省情况下， SSH 始终位于端口 22 上。
SSH is always on port 22 by default.
您可以将端口更改为其他内容。
You can change the port to something else.
你想做什么都行
Anything else you want.
那还没在用呢
Well, that's not already being used.
这有助于人们不断地攻击你的服务器
Which it helps a little bit with people
constantly attacking your server cuz they
在端口 22 上了解 SSH 。
know SSH on port 22.
但我们认为安全高于安全
But we call that security above security.
你觉得你更安全是因为我的门在下面
You think you're more safe because you're
like, my door's actually down here.
你觉得更安全
And you feel safer.
但这并不是一件真实的事情。
But that's not a real thing.
在安全和计算史上有一些教训
There are lessons in the history
of security and computing,
安全性高于安全性，这将使您长期处于安全状态。
security above security is the one
that will get you in the long run.
试图模糊事物，人们不知道 SSH 的任何内容，因此
Trying to obscure things,
people don't know SSH anything, so
他们必须知道选择一个不同的港口
they have to know to
choose a different port.
还有你可能会忘了港口是什么
And also,
you'll probably forget what the port is.
老实说你应该更安全吗
And honestly you should just be
more secure in general, yes?
>> 演讲者 2: 这与更改用户名如何不同 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: How is that different
than changing the user name, though?
>> Jem Young: 从?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: From?
>> 演讲者 2: 从 root 到您所选择的任何内容，我的意思是，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: From root to whatever you
chose, I mean you're making it more
默默无闻 怎么样啊
obscure.
How was it?
为什么要同时更改用户和端口号 ?
Why wouldn't it be good to change
both the user and the port number?
>> Jem Young: 你可以
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: You could and
通常当人们把电脑设置为很多时候都是这样做的
generally when people set up computers
a lot of times thet do that.
更改用户名不太适用于安全性，
Changing the username was not so
much for security,
就像我们不想无礼的一样
so much as we don't wanna be rude.
这只是个危险的地方我们得换个用户
It's just a dangerous place to be and
we're gonna have to switch users.
是啊它能帮助很小很小的一点
Yeah, it helps a tiny, tiny bit.
但我不会说那是为了安全
But again,
I would not ever say that's for security.
只是因为这是个好的做法
It's just because it's
a good practice to do.
问得好
But good question.
但是，愚昧的安全从来就不是一个很好的例子。
But yeah, security by obscurity is never,
never good example.
你甚至会说我要把我的服务器
You might even say like I'm
gonna set up my server and
没把保安放在它的库上谁会找到它
not put any security on it cuz it's like,
who's gonna find it?
有人会找到的他们会明白的
Someone will find it and they will get it.
我向你保证他们会的
[LAUGH] I promise you, they will.
所以我们就得离开这里
So we're just gonna wq out of here.
>> Jem Young: 我们接下来要做的是更改配置，但是
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And the next thing we wanna
do is we change the configuration but
因为该守护程序总是在运行，所以并不总是检查配置。
because that daemon's always running,
it's not always checking the config.
因此，我们希望重新启动该服务。
So we wanna restart that service.
因此，要执行该操作，我们会说 sudo 服务 sshd SSH 守护程序并仅添加重新启动。
So to do that we say sudo service
sshd SSH daemon and just add restart.
你得登录两次没问题
You have to login twice, it's okay.
>> Jem Young: 因此 sudo 服务 sshd 重新启动。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So
sudo service sshd restart.
>> Jem Young: 现在，如果我做了一切，我将尝试登录
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And now if I did everything
correctly I'm gonna try to log in as
它不会再让我失望了
roots and it won't let me anymore.
这意味着我们把它做好了
That means we configured it properly.
好了，我们在，禁止 root 用户登录。
All right, we're in,
we disable the root login.
我感觉好多了
I'm feeling better about that.
如果我们需要和 sudo 一起的话，我们就有了根。
We have root if we ever need to with sudo.
但是，我们不想在根上做任何事情，除非你真的很懒。
But again, we don't wanna do things on
root, unless you're just really lazy.
你不想一直这样做但是
You don't wanna type
sudo all the time but.
嗯。
Yes.
>> 扬声器 2: 因此，我们都需要重新启动系统。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So
we both have System restart required.
你觉得那是什么
What do you think that is?
>> Jem Young: 每当您运行大型更新或升级时，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: It does that every time
you run a large update or upgrade,
它会说重启你的系统
it's gonna say restart your system.
我们能做的是把盒子关掉，而我们实际上并没有把盒子关掉，
What we can do is turn the box off, while
we're not actually turned the box off,
我们把小部分的盒子都关掉了
we're turning our tiny little
fraction of a box off.
把它重新打开我会解决的
And turn it back on and I'll fix that.
但现在，这并不是现在的重要问题。
But for now,
it's not that important for now.
一会儿就会了
Later it will be.
稍后我们将讨论流程管理器，
And later we'll talk
about process managers,
这意味着当你处于某种程度的时候，如何得到你需要的一切
which means how to get everything you
need up and running when you're sort of
与必须手动启动并保持其正常运行的研究。
research versus having to start it
manually and then keep it up and running.
但那一会儿就会好了
But that'll be a little bit later.
问得好
But good question.
但现在别出汗了
But for now, don't sweat that too much.
我们有根
We have root.
如果你真的想要的话，你可以继续以 root用户的方式做事。
If you really want,
you can keep doing things as root.
我不推荐它 [ LAUGH]。
I don't recommend it [LAUGH].
如果你这么做你会有自己的
You are on your own if you do that.